CA Anushka Agrawal

Phone: +91-7240875367

E-Mail: agrawalanushka97@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://in.linkedin.com/in/anushka-agrawal-b79965118

Summary

An experienced Chartered Accountant with over 2 years of post qualification experience in auditing and financial analysis honed at PwC SDC PRIVATE LIMITED and S.C. KWATRA & CO. Excelled in enhancing financial accuracy and compliance, leveraging skills in GAAP, IFRS and Microsoft excel. Known for exceptional problem-solving abilities and teamwork, significantly contributing to process improvements and efficiency initiatives.

Experience

Audit Associate - 10/2021 to 05/2024

PwC SDC Private Limited, Bangalore, India

- Responsible for performing substantive audit procedures, gathering audit evidences and documenting them while performing audit of financial statements for U.S. based asset and wealth management funds including Private equity funds and Hedge funds in accordance with US GAAP and PwC audit methodology, resulting in the identification and correction of misstatements.
- Enhanced the audit processes by integrating automation using Alteryx which reduced the audit cycle time substantively.
- Facilitated collaboration between onshore and offshore teams to ensure comments on financials and on other audit areas are clear on time.
- Anticipated problems/issues and keep manager informed of engagement status; notify manager when billable hours will exceed or be under budget.
- Trained junior team members on audit procedures, delegated and reviewed their work and provided timely feedback.
- Performed audit completion procedures in the absence of senior members of the team independently and ensured completion of the audit within due date.
- Complied with firm's management procedures/systems and participated in firm wide initiatives to improve processes and efficiency.

Article Associate - 08/2016 to 08/2019

S.C. Kwatra & Co., New Delhi, India

- Executed statutory audit and tax audit for various clients in line with the firm's auditing practices and in compliance with auditing standards and legal regulations.
- Performed Scoping and preparation of audit plans for Internal audits for clients engaged in Manufacturing, Education, FMCG industries and Not for profit Research Institutes, NGOs ensuring compliance of Internal controls implemented by the management and suggesting improvements when required.
- Prepared financial statements including balance sheets, income statements and cash flow statements.
- Preparation of computation of income and filing of Income tax returns, ensuring CARO compliance.
- Processed payroll and calculated correct amount incorporating overtime, deductions, bonuses etc. with assistance of computer systems.
- Preparation of AOC-4 and MGT-7 returns.

Skill Highlights

- Financial analysis and audit
- U.S. Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (US GAAP)
- International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS)
- Indian Accounting Standards (IND AS)
- Internal controls

- Microsoft excel proficiency
- Microsoft Office
- Alteryx
- Other accounting and audit softwares eg. Tally erp, Busy, Computax, Aura, SAP, Microsoft D365, Quick Books

Education

Chartered Accountancy - Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (June 2014 - June 2021)

- CA CPT June 2014
- CA IPCC November, 2016
- CA Final June 2021

Bachelor of commerce (B.Com) - Jiwaji University, Gwalior (April 2014 - May 2017)